Sunil Kumar

sunilkumarsheoran@gmail.com +1-6043674432 linkedin.com/in/sunilkumarsheoran ECS 412, University of Victoria, Victoria, BC, Canada. V8P 5C2

I am a student of Master of Computer Science at the University of Victoria. I have 3 years of software development experience with software product companies. I am seeking co-op opportunities where I can fully use my skills for the success of an organization and learn new skills on cutting edge technologies in the industry.

Education

M.Sc. in Computer Science Jan 2019 - Expected Dec 2020 University of Victoria, BC, Canada. - 7.33 / 9.0 GPA

Projects: Training a DQN agent for Coinrun (github.com/Unimax/coinrun-dqn-pytorch) and Matchmaking for online multiplayer games (git.io/JenE4).

B.Tech. in Information Technology Aug 2010-May 2014 NIT Durgapur, West Bengal, India. - 8.10 / 10.0 CGPA Projects: Collage Study Point Website (git.io/JenEB), Digital Clock on Multisim and Exploration bot.

Technical Skills

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, Python, Golang, SQL, C, C++, PHP, CSS, HTML.
- Tools & Frameworks: Docker, Kubernetes, gRPC, Git, REST APIs, Google Web Toolkit (GWT), JDBC, Hibernate, Electron, Angular, Eclipse Modeling Framework (EMF), JasperReports, Excel.
- Concepts: OOPs, Data Structures, Deep Learning.
- Operating Systems: Linux, Windows

Experience

Technical Associate / Zillious Solutions, New Delhi, India.

July 2018 - Dec 2018

- Developed a solution for a long-standing issue with java enum reaching its size limit, with minimum changes in the application.
- Added support for customizable vouchers and integrated multiple payment gateways including Razorpay, Paytm, etc.
- Integrated a pre-developed machine learning model into the application for finding duplicate hotels. Decreased the time for marking duplicate hotels by 90% in live search results for hotels.

Software Developer / Drishti-Soft Solutions, Gurugram, India.

June 2014 - Sep 2016

- Awarded with Excellence Award 2016 and won /tmp 2014 a 10 days 24x7 coding event.
- Majorly worked on Ameyo Report, a GWT based front-end, and Jasper based backend; This includes a UI renew, backend enhancements and automating the generation of *Transformers*, a data de-normalization component, by using EMF modeling.
- Created a report scheduler based on the Quartz library with support for centralized reporting and graphical reports.
- Increased performance for a large customer's reporting database by 90% using table partition and multicolumn indexes.
- Increased performance of a statics managing component by 60% using soft references based cache for reflective calls.
- Developed a context-aware report designer with the Front-end based on GWT with data populating based on EMF model instances and outputs a proprietary file format (.drxml) which converted by the backend into a JasperReports based object. It was used to give demos to international customers as a future project.
- Created Magic Numbers: Predicts hardware requirements (CPU, RAM, and HDD) based on customer functional requirements.
- Delivered components for the automation of the collection process for an Indian Bank. Implemented a fresh UI, Integrating Hitachi Content Platform (HCP) for report storage, created a custom SSO authentication server & various domain-specific features like *Centralized Exclusion*.
- Interviewed candidates, prepared questions and did the training for new employees for the 2016 and 2017 hiring seasons.

Software Developer Intern / Morphing Machines, Bangalore, India.

June 2013 – Aug 2013

Designed and developed the front-end interface for a research project called 'Development of A Flexible Framework for A
Network On Chip'. We wrote a research paper about it (git.io/Jen9I).

Personal Interests

- Video Games: Won 2nd place in COBX and Aorus Land 2017 National DOTA 2 tournaments, 1st place in Playtonia Delhi and Indian LAN Gaming Cup Delhi DOTA 2 tournaments.
- Karate: Green belt in Shito Ryu Shūkōkai Karate.
- Solving Programming Problems: Won 1st place in *Behind the Scene* 2013, 1st place in *InCanity* 2013 and 2nd place in Simplex 2012.
- Playing Chess: 3rd, 1st and 2nd place in Regional Sports Meet in 2007, 2006 and 2005. Won a place in K.V. National Sports Meet.

References

- Sahil Gandhi (sahilgandhi2011@gmail.com) Product Evangelist, Ameyo (previously known as Drishti-Soft Solutions).
- **Dr. Hausi Müller** (<u>hausi@uvic.ca</u>) Professor, University of Victoria.